Hat dich der 7. Oktober verändert?
Oh yes it did.
Before October 7th,
I thought that I was very brave and that,
unlike my family,
I'm not going to move around because of terror.
But
when the level of terror reached
the level of terror that they went through in Libya,
or in any other place in the Middle East...
I remember so well the stories from Libya,
there's one story that I remember that my mom told me,
that her uncle used to keep a can of gasoline,
a big can of gasoline in his house because
he said that if the mob ever gets to his house,
it will be a much better fate
for the family to be burnt alive,
rather than be caught by the mob.
So, I heard all the stories,
about
women that they cut the breasts off
or pregnant
women with bellies cut open.
We heard all those stories,
I must say that we've never dwelled in them.
I've never went like
"Free, free my grandparents house in Libya"
Never happened,
even though it’s a very catchy tune.
But all they wanted was to run away to Israel,
and have their haven. have their...
Their place, you know.
Having been originated in this region,
I think that there must be a haven
in the Middle East for me.
And there isn't. There isn't.
Not for me, not for my children.
Because even when being limited to the tiny,
tiny Israel, I can’t have a quiet life over here,
in this area.
So...
After October 7th,
I don’t know,
if I will be able to be that link in the chain,
that did not submit to terror.
Time will tell. Right now,
I took another year outside of the kibbutz,
we still haven’t come back.
My son is also a very important
element here,
because he cannot run for shelter in a few seconds.
We need to see,
this threat needs to be lifted off our shoulders.
People around the world don’t really understand it.
They don’t understand
How important it is
to dismantle Hamas.
Because firstly,
from all the Palestinians that I had known
throughout the years,
the stories I hear about Hamas when their
people are over here and they're not,
there are horrible stories.
And if you want to call yourself a
left cleaning person or humanitarian person,
you wouldn’t want anyone in the world,
anyone, to be ruled by someone like that.
They are torturing both sides of the borders.
Don’t be mistaken.
The second thing is that
there are so many things that people don’t know.
Living with
that threat over your head 24/7,
there are things in life that
you can’t even think about,
but they're in the back of my mind all the time:
I will never wear high heels.
Never. My shoes will be always good enough for running.
If my child is sick and he's in his bedroom,
which is the bomb shelter of the house,
and I need to get some fresh air inside,
I will have to think twice:
"Wait, is it safe enough today?"
to open the iron shutters of the bomb shelters,
or is it not?
I can be with my children in the playground,
and have drizzles of rockets coming in
within seconds, like that.
"4 seconds, get shelter, take shelter".
This threat needs to be lifted off our shoulders.
And anyone who sits thousands
of miles away
and thinks that this is something that is acceptable,
please again bring your family over here.
Bring your children, bring your great grandchildren,
raise them where I raise mine.
I promise you, on my porch with a wine,
A lovely chit chat
on the fine arts of resilience and retaliation.
But until you do that, you don’t really get to say
about how I protect my children,
because most of the people...
Let me articulate it like this...
Let me put it like this:
The gap between what people think
they know about this region,
and reality, is scary.
And imagine,
and look what the Middle East looked like
hundreds of years ago. Just look what it looked like,
and what it has become today.
For us as Middle Easterns,
and I also speak,
with Kurds and with Druze and with
different friends that I have,
from different ethnicities around the Middle East,
they don’t understand.
The ignorance of people about our region is frightening,
it’s really frightening.
And if October 7 changed me? It absolutely did.
Absolutely did.